

Esteban Basili

Full Stack Web Developer | Architect | BIM Specialist

Details

+49 1520 9431181
me@estebanbasili.com
www.estebanbasili.com
Linkedin
GitHub

Skills

Creative Thinking
Leadership
Resourcefulness
Organisational
Solutions oriented
Iterative working
Motivating others
Strategic Thinking
Openness to criticism
Drive and Initiative

Technical skills

Dev Stack

HTML and CSS

Javascript

MongoDB

Express.js

React.js

Node.js

Git and GitHub

Python

AEC Technologies

Revit

Dynamo

BIM 360

Aconex

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a sensibility for human-centred design, user experience and multidisciplinarity as key values to create meaningful and impactful products.

Architect and BIM Specialist with more than 10 years of experience in design and construction, and engaged in the digitalisation of the industry.

Professional Experience

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, Ironhack

May 2022 - Jul 2022 Remote.

- Project 1. The Museum Visitor (Link to site GitHub).
- Project 2. PlantApp (Link to site GitHub).
- Project 3. PSC Pet Social Club (Link to site GitHub Back Front).

Sabbatical

Oct 2021 - Mar 2022 Mexico, Costa Rica, Argentina, Brazil.

Project Architect and BIM Specialist, Hyphen A GmbH

Oct 2018 - Sep 2021 Berlin, Germany.

- Managed the BIM data production and exchange in projects of the logistic sector for Amazon (from 60.000m² to 100.000m²).
- Led the BIM Coordination processes of a team of 10 and up to 6 sub-contractors, gaining expertise in understanding BEP, EIR and CDE platforms.
- Developed BIM Standards, more than 50 families and dynamo scripts.
- Co-ordinated in-house training in BIM authoring tools and tutored my colleagues during the development of the projects.

Architect, Partner and BIM Specialist, IR arquitectura

Jun 2015 - Ago 2018 Buenos Aires, Argentina.

- Managed 4 projects and collaborated in other 10, from schematic design throughout design development to construction administration.
- Developed standards inspired by the Agile methodology in project management collaborative workflows and project phases transitions.
- Promoted the digitalization of the workflows and BIM Implementation.

Consulting Architect on industrial wood houses, Tapebicuá

Feb 2018 - Sep 2018 Gobernador Virasoro, Argentina.

 Consulted the management team in the design and construction phase, reducing the overall lead times by 20%. **Navisworks**

Autocad

Revizto

Solibri

Bluebeam Revu

3ds Max

Revit Teacher Assistant. BIM Course

Feb 2018 - Sep 2018 Universidad de Buenos Aires.

 Collaborated as a Teacher Assistant in the class led by Arch. Javier Nuñez.

Revit Teacher. Revit a Medida

Feb 2017 - Jan 2019 Buenos Aires, Argentina.

• Ran one-on-one and group lessons of Revit and BIM.

Graphic Design

Indesign

Illustrator

Photoshop

Arch. Designer/Intern, 4L Arquitectura/KLM Arquitectos/A3 Arquitectos

Mar 2010 - May 2015 Buenos Aires.

Languages • Collaborated on schematic design, design competitions and architectural

Spanish. Native.

Education

English. Proficient.

First Certificate (C1),

Cambridge University.

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, Ironhack

May 2022 - Jul 2022 Remote.

visualisation.

German. Intermediate.

Zertifikat Deutsch (B2.2),

Goethe Institut.

Architect Diploma, Universidad de Buenos Aires.

Mar 2007 - May 2015 Buenos Aires, Argentina.

• 6 years Degree, Facultad de Arquitectura, Diseño y Urbanismo.